Diego Duarte Fernández

Software Developer

OBJECTIVE

My principal goal in the computer science area is to contribute significantly to the business world through the application of my tech knowledge and soft skills. I constantly seek to improve my capabilities to offer innovative and efficient technological solutions that add value to company operations. I have worked supporting and creating software for small companies also, I've created some personal projects.

REFERENCES

Mariana Rivas Villatoro

Informatic Business Career Coordinator villatoro@gmail.com

Daniel Calderón Díaz

Data Engineer at LTVco calde0601@gmail.com

ADDRESS

Limón, Limón, Costa Rica

PHONE

+506 64832448

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2022 - JAN 2022 - Java | Arduino | Processing

SIGCHI Event | It was a technology event where I implemented my programming skills to solve a random environmental problem and me and my team got first place with the best proposal to solve the exploitation of natural resources problem.

AUG 2023 - MAY 2024 - Express | React | MySQL | MaterialUI

Dalopcan Company | This project is part of a university requirement called TCU, which consists of supporting companies through technology. The software solution is made up of 3 parts: database, API, and front-end application. In this project you can manage the clinical records that the company uses to keep track of its clients/patients.

MAR 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022 - WordPress | HTML | CSS3

Gandoca Tours Company | This is a web app made in WordPress and WooCommerce. My role in this project was support it, fixed errors and create new content and sections.

MAR 2023 - JUN 2023 - PHP | Angular | MySQL | Bootstrap

Funko Pop Academic Project | This is a college project in which we can manage inventory of a Funko's Shopping Cart. This project was created building and API using the microframework Slim and the frontend client with Angular.

EDUCATION

UCR Bachelor's degree Business Computing 2020-2024 (80% of career)

CUNLIMON Diploma in business computing 2018 - 2020

INA Technician in design and development of web applications. 2018 - 2019

EMAIL

diegoduarte8343@gmail.com

WEBSITE

https://diegoport.netlify.app

LANGUAGES

Spanish | Native Language English | B1+

SKILS

Soft Skills:

- 1. I have experience effectively communicating ideas to an audience.
- 2. I have created projects in team, and it is the best way to construct a software product.
- 3. I am open to getting advice for improving my soft and tech skills.

Tech Skills:

Nodejs | Python | MySQL | Git | HTML | CSS3 | React | Bootstrap